MD SADAB SAQIB

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India



sadabnepal1993@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/sadabnepal



+91 7899423030



https://github.com/sadabnepal

Summary

An enthusiast Test Engineer with 5.5 years of total experience, with 4.5 years in Testing.

Experienced in developing different framework from scratch using Selenium, Java, WebdriverlO, Typescript, RestAssured, BDD, TDD, Mocha.

Deployed the project in CI pipeline such as Bamboo, Jenkins.

Experience in working with small and large teams, collaborating with developers

Mentoring team members to take up automation skills

Experience



Consultant - Test Automation Engineer

Capgemini

Mar 2020 - Present (1 year +)

- * Developed mocha framework using WebdriverIO and Typescript for end to end regression testing resulted in saving 60 hours per sprint.
- * Developed BDD framework using Rest-assured and Java from scratch for back-end testing resulted in saving 2 execution days.
- * Configured CI pipeline using bamboo, supported in setting up Jenkins jobs.
- * Converting business scenario document into feature, creating test plan, test execution, bug reporting.
- * Participating manual testing as and when required to validate application data against json API response response recorded using Postman.
- * Participating in code review, daily stand-up call, defect triage, mentoring team members to take up automation activities.

Test Engineer

Wipro Limited

Oct 2018 - Feb 2020 (1 year 5 months)

- * Prepared test case and executed manual System Testing and Regression testing...
- * Built automated test framework from scratch using AssureNXT (Selenium based GUI Tool).
- * Test Automation scripts maintenance such as providing script fix, modifying script, adding new features

Test Automation Engineer

Wipro Limited

Jul 2016 - Sep 2018 (2 years 3 months)

- * Participated in automating test cases using existing Automation Framework built using Selenium Webdriver, TestNG, Page Object Model and ServiceNow ATF
- * Executed automation script on daily basis from quality center, shared report to client.
- * Identified the pain areas in project & providing solutions using Selenium Automation

Project Engineer

Wipro Limited

Sep 2015 - Jun 2016 (10 months)

Worked on Active Directory and Exchange. User account creation, modification and deletion.

- * File Share creation, deletion, granting access to users via Active Directory groups.
- * SharePoint Access Management via Active Directory.
- * Escalation contact, On-call contact creation in SharePoint site.
- * Handled critical incidents adhering SOP defined by organization.

Education



Jamal Mohamed College

Bachelor of Computer Science, Computer Science 2012 - 2015



Tribhuvan University

Higher Secondary School Certificate 2009 - 2010

Licenses & Certifications



now Micro Certification - Automated Test Framework - ServiceNow

sadabnepal1993@gmail.com

Skills

Selenium • Selenium WebDriver • Java • WebdriverIO • TypeScript • REST APIs • Atlassian Bamboo • Jenkins • Mocha (JavaScript Framework) • GitHub

Honors & Awards



Quality Performance Award - Corning Incorporated

Excellent contribution towards ServiceNow upgrade project from Kingstone to Madrid version within committed timeline and with minimal business impact.